<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>pnppl.cc</title>
        <link>https://pnppl.cc/+/feed.rss</link>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <description></description>
        <item>
            <title>pnppl</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/pnppl&#34;&gt;pnppl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-the-hell-is-pnppl&#34;&gt;What the hell is &amp;quot;pnppl&amp;quot;? &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;what-the-hell-is-pnppl&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#what-the-hell-is-pnppl&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s me! &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/pnppl&#34;&gt;pnppl&lt;/a&gt; is my hacker name. My screen name. My handle. My nom de plume. My... nom de guerre?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why? &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;why&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#why&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can type it fast and it&#39;s usually not taken.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;okay-but-like-what-does-it-mean-where-did-it-come-from&#34;&gt;Okay but like... what does it mean? Where did it come from? &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;okay-but-like-what-does-it-mean-where-did-it-come-from&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#okay-but-like-what-does-it-mean-where-did-it-come-from&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It means nothing. It means me. The origin is not very interesting; you can probably figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, a friend of mine interprets it as P=NP.pl. This is much cooler and hackerier and I encourage you to read it that way, even though P≠NP and I&#39;ve never written a line of Perl in my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-is-it-pronounced&#34;&gt;How is it pronounced? &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;how-is-it-pronounced&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#how-is-it-pronounced&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I say it &amp;quot;pee-nipple&amp;quot;, but I&#39;m also four years old. Please feel free to invent a more dignified pronunciation. Maybe make the &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt;s silent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;are-you-a-swinger&#34;&gt;Are you a swinger? &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;are-you-a-swinger&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#are-you-a-swinger&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not yet, but my inbox is always open.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/meta&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;meta&#34; name=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#meta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-31T09:21:36-05:00</pubDate>
            <guid>pnppl</guid>
            <link>https://pnppl.cc/pnppl</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>about</title>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-pnpplcc&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/about&#34;&gt;About pnppl.cc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;about-pnpplcc&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#about-pnpplcc&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;She started keeping a journal — had been, in fact, secretly doing so for some time: the furtive act of a deranged person.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;— &lt;a href=&#34;https://annas-archive.li/search?q=valis&#34;&gt;PKD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commonplace_book&#34;&gt;commonplace&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s also, perhaps, my digital garden? I won&#39;t be offended if you just call it my blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been a prodigious note-taker for years. Being able to carry my notes with me and search them digitally means I can actually refer back to them, and often do. It recently occurred to me that some of these notes (when tidied up a bit) might be of interest to other people. I call this site a commonplace because it&#39;s an attempt to translate that existing practice into a public form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also write stuff that I don&#39;t refer to but is hopefully valuable in other ways: fiction, essays, code, etc. And since I&#39;m at it anyway, I might as well post art I make that doesn&#39;t fit in a text file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope that sharing my commonplace publicly will encourage me to write more, more intentionally, for a wider audience. It would be especially nice if it made me actually document my tech projects so I don&#39;t have to re-figure them out whenever I come back to them after a long time. I said I was a prodigious note-taker, not a good one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;copyleft&#34;&gt;Copyleft &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;copyleft&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#copyleft&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site is licensed &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;, with the attribution requirement waived.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Intellectual property is a fake idea; unfortunately, we live in a world where it reigns supreme. Copyleft gives us a tool to turn copyright against itself. It means that you can do whatever you want with the content of this site, as long as you extend the same right to others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not wild about this specific license. It&#39;s irritating that it requires notice of attribution and derivatives. I don&#39;t care what you do with my work as long as you don&#39;t &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enclosure&#34;&gt;enclose&lt;/a&gt; it. Still, CC BY-SA 4.0 seems to be on strong legal footing and is compatible with (and can even be converted into) the GPLv3. If the license causes issues for you, let me know and I&#39;ll probably be happy to do a public domain declaration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;install-victor-mono&#34;&gt;Install Victor Mono &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;install-victor-mono&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#install-victor-mono&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site really looks much better in &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubjo.github.io/victor-mono/&#34;&gt;Victor Mono&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s my favorite font. Even though it&#39;s monospace, it&#39;s a pleasure to read.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I could force it on you, but I find that rude. I block remote fonts in my browser: they&#39;re usually hosted on Google&#39;s CDN, so they call home; they&#39;re a multi-megabyte blob you have to download just to read some text; and they don&#39;t respect your preference of default font. So, please install it. I promise you&#39;ll like it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, if you&#39;re on an Android phone, I think you have to be rooted to install a font and it&#39;s a big pain in the ass.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;we-have-to-go-deeper-technical-details-etc&#34;&gt;We have to go deeper: technical details, etc. &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;we-have-to-go-deeper-technical-details-etc&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#we-have-to-go-deeper-technical-details-etc&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My goal is to have to change as little as possible about my existing approach to writing: plaintext, formatted in whatever way feels right, written in my notes app or shell. I&#39;d like for the software to adapt to me, not the other way around. My one concession is Markdown. I don&#39;t really like it, but it&#39;s cornered the market, and it&#39;s close enough that I&#39;m willing to bend a little. Extensions make it much less painful — particularly Wikilink syntax support. The text files that &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/pnppl&#34;&gt;pnppl&lt;/a&gt;.cc is built from are the One True Commonplace, with the website providing some extra features that are nice to have but not required. You can access the original text file for a post with the &lt;em&gt;src&lt;/em&gt; button in the top right corner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also access them through &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.gay/pnppl/pnppl.cc/&#34;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/pnppl/pnppl.cc&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pnppl/pnppl.cc&#34;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;, which handily doubles as a version history and complete source of the site. I&#39;d like to make it more convenient, but for now you can use &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; to grab all of the posts at once.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;git clone -n --depth&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ff79c6&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#bd93f9&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; --filter&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ff79c6&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;tree:0 https://git.gay/pnppl/pnppl.cc.git &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ff79c6&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#8be9fd;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; pnppl.cc &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ff79c6&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;git sparse-checkout &lt;span style=&#34;color:#8be9fd;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;set&lt;/span&gt; --no-cone /site/txt &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ff79c6&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;git checkout&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/pnppl&#34;&gt;pnppl&lt;/a&gt;.cc does not use any Javascript, although there might be a search page in the future that uses it. The software this site is based on actually has search as an option, but it fell prey to my elimination of Javascript.  It&#39;s a bit silly that the public version of my notebook, which only became indispensible to me due to the search feature, does not actually have a search right now. It&#39;s just important to me that my site reflect what I hope to see online. For the time being, if you want to search, you can grab the text files and search them locally. This is easily accomplished in the shell, eg &lt;code&gt;grep -i &amp;quot;search term&amp;quot; *.md&lt;/code&gt;. I like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep&#34;&gt;ripgrep&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A major goal I have is for the site to be usable as plain HTML. The sites that have stood the test of time, that still display perfectly and are a pleasure to read, are all plain old HTML. (Usually hosted on URLs like &lt;code&gt;http://lab.cs.mit.edu/faculty/~johnsmith&lt;/code&gt; and miraculously preserved in their entirety by the Wayback Machine.) As a fan of retrocomputing, I&#39;d also like to be able to access my site on anything with a web browser, and trying to accomplish that level of compatibility is the stuff of web design nightmares... unless it&#39;s just plain old HTML. To that end, I&#39;ve been testing the site in progress on NCSA Mosaic v2.7b6. Sure, it&#39;s the last version... but it&#39;s the last version of the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; major browser, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AppImageCommunity/NCSA-Mosaic-AppImage&#34;&gt;I can run it on my computer.&lt;/a&gt; I figure if it works in Mosaic, it ought to work in anything. HTML is wonderfully resilient. Pretty much every browser ever made happily displays malformed HTML without issue. Modern browsers still render supposedly obsolete tags just fine, and Mosaic will just ignore tags it doesn&#39;t understand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With legacy compatibility covered, we can use stylesheets to make the site pretty on a modern browser, since CSS doesn&#39;t make them slow to a crawl or execute arbitrary code. Now, I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; web design, and I find CSS particularly frustrating, so I&#39;ve relied on the stylesheet that xlog came with as a starting point. It uses a big framework and is much larger than I&#39;d like at 200K (uncompressed — was originally 4x the size, compressed), but it handles dark mode, responsiveness, etc., which all sounds exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I selected &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/emad-elsaid/xlog&#34;&gt;xlog&lt;/a&gt; as the best static site generator for my requirements: everything I cared about still worked with Javascript disabled and it supported must-have features: backlinks and mentions. (The way mentions work is that when the name of a post is used in another post, it&#39;s automatically turned into a link. Backlink support adds a section at the foot of a post that lists all the other posts that link to it.) If I&#39;m going hypertext, I want all the benefits, but I also don&#39;t want to spend a lot of time fussing over the website when it&#39;s the words that really matter. And given the wide variety of subjects, it would be nice to have some ability to discover posts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For mentions, the underline is broken with dashes to de-emphasize it and so you can distinguish it from a manual link. External links are followed by a % sign, because it kind of looks like an X and also kind of like the little external link symbol a bunch of sites use. I wanted to keep it ASCII when possible, as well as webfont-free. HTML entities are fair game though, provided they work in Mosaic, which is where the section (§) and not (¬ — returns you to the table of contents) come from that appear when you hover a heading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Still, I&#39;m not quite willing to give up UTF-8 for my posts. UTF-8 is so good. I&#39;m addicted to the emdash. Sometimes I even use an emoji. I figure a garbled character here and there in the unlikely event that someone actually uses Mosaic or another legacy browser is an acceptable sacrifice. I may change my mind if I end up spending a lot of time reading on a legacy system, or if anyone actually reads this and cares. It wouldn&#39;t be too hard to change. I also like the idea of making it available via Gopher for the true low-tech heads. We&#39;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/meta&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;meta&#34; name=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#meta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-31T09:21:31-05:00</pubDate>
            <guid>about</guid>
            <link>https://pnppl.cc/about</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026-01-08_evil</title>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;evil&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;Evil&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;evil&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#evil&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/essay&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;essay&#34; name=&#34;essay&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#essay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/politics&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;politics&#34; name=&#34;politics&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/ethics&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;ethics&#34; name=&#34;ethics&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#ethics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the rise of Donald Trump&#39;s fascist regime in particular and global democratic backsliding in general, I&#39;ve often found myself contemplating the nature of &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;evil&lt;/a&gt;. We see it every day, but are still shocked by it, even those of us who are embittered and cynical and well aware that it is not a new phenomenon. Abject &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;evil&lt;/a&gt; is so foreign to decent minds that it invites a toxic empathy: I&#39;m sure I&#39;m not the only one who looks aghast at the latest horror of the day and reflexively wonders, &amp;quot;but why? how could they do this?&amp;quot;, even though I know it is pointless. There is an unbridgeable chasm between us and these monsters that my mind can never quite accept. It&#39;s as though I think there&#39;s One Weird Trick that would enable me to look at nightmarish brutality and say &amp;quot;I may not agree, but I understand.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I strongly suspect this process of kneejerk empathy is a major part of the story of fascism&#39;s persistence. Empathy is not just about being nice or sympathetic; it&#39;s a process whereby we model the internal state of external people. Empathy is as necessary for anticipating the tactics of an opposing force as it is for comforting a friend.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; name=&#34;fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The upshot is that fascism acts as a mimetic hazard. We can&#39;t fight what we don&#39;t understand, and we can&#39;t understand fascism without part of our minds being dedicated to simulating — that is to say, replicating — the thought processes of fascists. In other words, fascism is the ultimate cop in your head: it&#39;s both a system of brutal political tyranny and a form of psychological warfare to produce same.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; name=&#34;fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, we can&#39;t let ourselves off the hook. Just because you aren&#39;t rounding up people of color and shooting civilians in the face doesn&#39;t mean you&#39;re in the clear. That sort of self-congratulation is incredibly harmful because nobody wants to think of themselves as a Bad Person. If our moral universe is built on dividing people into Good and Bad, it will only grease the wheels of bad behavior by implicitly justifying every action by a Good Person. This of course raises the question of whether &amp;quot;evil&amp;quot; is even a coherent category, whether I&#39;m just wasting my time by writing this essay. Besides that I simply don&#39;t want to write about meta-ethics — and at the risk of recapitulating foolishness like deontology and the N.A.P. — I think the conclusions I&#39;ve come to hold some value for thinking about the nature of human social problems, even if they wouldn&#39;t satisfy a moral philosopher.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-tripartite-face-of-evil&#34;&gt;The Tripartite Face of &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;Evil&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;the-tripartite-face-of-evil&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#the-tripartite-face-of-evil&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cruelty&#34;&gt;Cruelty &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;cruelty&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#cruelty&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cruelty is the most visible, blatant form of &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;evil&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s what slaps us in the face every morning. It&#39;s what the regime seems to take a particular delight in spreading against its targets; it&#39;s what the far-right has successfully gamified via social media into a competition over who can be the nastiest person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not all meanness constitutes cruelty. Cruelty is specifically an &lt;em&gt;excess&lt;/em&gt; of meanness over and above what the situation calls for, and tends to delight in itself. Screaming at an ICE agent that he has a small dick is meanness; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnestyusa.org/reports/torture-and-enforced-disappearances-in-the-sunshine-state-human-rights-violations-at-alligator-alcatraz-and-krome-in-florida/&#34;&gt;what ICE agents do is cruelty.&lt;/a&gt; Torture is the paradigmatic example of cruelty as it inflicts pain on its victims without any possibility of furthering a legitimate goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cruelty is what happens when we gratuitously indulge the darker side of our nature, but it&#39;s not just an individual pathology: infliction of gratuitous harm is built into our society&#39;s structure, from the way our food is produced (millions of laborers subjected to harsh conditions and poverty wages; billions of nonhuman animals, born in captivity and tortured to death) to the pointless misery inflicted on unwanted people groups on a daily basis (non-white/&amp;quot;foreign&amp;quot; people murdered in front of their family or rounded up and put in a concentration camp; women raped without recourse, forced to carry a pregnancy to term; widespread denigration of queer, trans, disabled, and neurodivergent people; people reduced to begging for scraps in the street from people with money to spare who won&#39;t even look at them; healthcare routinely denied to almost everyone) to the entire &amp;quot;justice system&amp;quot; with its violence, rape, legalized slavery, and endless petty bureaucracy that gradually wears down the victim&#39;s dignity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cruelty is what we think of when we think of &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;evil&lt;/a&gt;: the madman in a horror movie smiling as he eviscerates a stranger; animal abuse; Nazi death camps. It&#39;s not hard to identify egregious examples like this. Even so, Team Decency is still eminently capable of cruelty, often justified as a way to fight Team &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;Evil&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s not always clear where the line should be drawn between necessary acts of meanness or violence and unnecessary acts of cruelty, but we should make an effort to draw it and to step back from the brink. Self-justification is seductively easy, and cruelty has a way of spreading and corroding the decency of others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;Evil&lt;/a&gt; without cruelty is far more tolerable, but tends to produce cruelty in the end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;willful-ignorance&#34;&gt;Willful Ignorance &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;willful-ignorance&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#willful-ignorance&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s nothing wrong with being stupid, but there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; something wrong with choosing to remain stupid when given the option, and there is something &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; wrong with actively cultivating your own stupidity. Willful ignorance is a substantial contributing factor to the persistence of systemic cruelty and other social ills, from climate change to homophobia to ChatGPT. Fascism thus heavily promotes it with relentless propaganda and a culture of anti-intellectualism. It is possible to spend your entire life in a carefully manufactured bubble of ignorance, and it&#39;s so comfortable that a great many people choose to do so. You can&#39;t have complex, difficult thoughts about things that you don&#39;t even know about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Fox News junkie of yesteryear and the social media brainrot nazi of today exemplify this willful ignorance. They blanket themselves in lies and half-truths, helpfully aided by a complicit media ecosystem. Anyone who threatens to pop the bubble is subjected to ridicule and aggressive regurgitation of the lies the willfully ignorant have chosen to swallow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This form of &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;evil&lt;/a&gt; also runs deep in the ranks of Team Decency, most obvious in liberals who were entirely comfortable with the system of oppression known as state capitalism until it inconvenienced them. An infamous protest sign proclaimed that &amp;quot;If Kamala was president, we&#39;d all be at brunch.&amp;quot; Avoiding mental inconvenience is also paramount: don&#39;t ruin brunch by telling us how it was made!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps less obvious, but no less widespread, is the willful ignorance the rest of us use in an attempt to avoid the psychological pain of our hellscape. It&#39;s incredibly tempting to just shut off the news, put on a TV show, and bury your head in a hole hoping it all goes away. It&#39;s easy to scroll past fundraisers and protest announcements that you know would compel you to contribute if you let yourself absorb it. We often justify willful ignorance with the language of self-care. Why burden yourself with knowledge if you can&#39;t do anything about it?&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; name=&#34;fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As important as it is to avoid burnout, refusal to engage is insidious and becomes a habit over time. Where do you think all those brunch liberals came from?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cowardice&#34;&gt;Cowardice &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;cowardice&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#cowardice&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One should never regret one&#39;s excesses, only one&#39;s failures of nerve.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;— &lt;a href=&#34;https://annas-archive.li/search?q=hydrogen+sonata&#34;&gt;Ximenyr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have long thought that cowardice is the ultimate root of our problems. The only thing necessary for the triumph of &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2026-01-08_evil&#34;&gt;evil&lt;/a&gt; is for decent people to do nothing. We are a planet of eight billion mostly decent people, but we let ourselves be ruled by a tiny minority of psychopaths. Human cowardice is so pervasive that we are easily cowed by simple peer pressure not backed by threat of force. Our society is directly analogous to a jail of 10,000 inmates imprisoned by ten guards, who keep us in line without even drawing a weapon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cowardice seems rational in the short-term. What if you rush the guards and nobody follows? Most of our collective problems persist through this short-sighted logic. Look at the bigger picture and it becomes obvious that the rational thing to do is to rush the guards, right away, every time. There are many more of us than there are of them, and they will keep stuffing more people inside the cage until we fight back. Courage is contagious, and the longer we wait, the harder the fight will become.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, you might lose; but there are fates worse than death, and knowing you&#39;re a coward is one of them. While I am resoundingly guilty of all three sins enumerated here, it&#39;s the cowardice that I really &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; guilty about. Am I really going to just watch them establish the Fourth Reich, even though I know that in the long run I would be better off fighting back? What about you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fear of being hurt or killed is not the only dangerous form of cowardice. Fear of being wrong also leads many of us to do nothing for fear that we&#39;ll mess things up worse. Humility and the law of unintended consequences can be paralyzing, at least until we&#39;re swept along by a mob. So what if you don&#39;t know for sure what&#39;s the right thing to do? Nobody does without access to a crystal ball. You still have to try, every opportunity you have, to fight like your life depends on it — because it does.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion-abdication-of-responsibility&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Abdication of Responsibility &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;conclusion-abdication-of-responsibility&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#conclusion-abdication-of-responsibility&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All three sins that I identified above have one thing in common: abdication of responsibility to ourselves and to each other. Having responsibilities sucks. We don&#39;t like to accept what feels like limits on our behavior, duties we didn&#39;t agree to. It&#39;s easier to not give a shit. Fill your head with TikTok sludge, torment a loser for fun, avoid anything challenging: this is a lifestyle that at first feels like freedom. No rules! Ice cream for dinner! That thin veneer will eventually wear away. You&#39;ll look up from your phone to discover the barrel of an ICE agent&#39;s gun pointed in your face, your friends absent, nothing in your heart but emptiness and nothing in your future but pain. What felt like freedom will be revealed as a cage you built around yourself. True freedom empowers you to build meaning, to fight for yourself and your loved ones, to live in daylight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nobody wants the responsibility to &amp;quot;be the adult&amp;quot; and clean up the messes we&#39;re faced with, but you cannot opt out. You can certainly try, but it will end badly for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;Footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;Footnotes&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#Footnotes&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is both the biggest weakness and the biggest strength of Team Decency. Fascists lack empathy and thus often fail miserably to understand their enemy (&lt;em&gt;ie&lt;/em&gt;, us). Just think of how often they act on intelligence bulletins that make fundamentally ridiculous claims about antifa wanting to burn down the forest or whatever. The fascist ecosystem is built on misinformation, so they base their actions on fundamentally mistaken (even cartoonish) understandings of reality. This can be exploited!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; name=&#34;fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I&#39;m right about this, it might go some way toward explaining collaborators&#39; fixation on defining fascist claims as reasonable. While the most egregious form of this tendency is probably deference to blatantly dishonest official statements which justify regime crimes as acts of self-defense, &lt;a href=&#34;/trans%20genocide&#34;&gt;/trans genocide&lt;/a&gt; offers more instructive illustrations: we are constantly informed that the deranged ravings of bloodthirsty bigots are actually &amp;quot;reasonable concerns&amp;quot;, encouraged to put ourselves in the shoes of hysterical paranoids, and expected to somehow compromise with the people who want us exterminated.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; name=&#34;fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you sure there&#39;s nothing you can do about it? If you remain wilfully ignorant, that&#39;s guaranteed. If not, you might discover an inconvenient moral duty.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; name=&#34;fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-31T09:19:53-05:00</pubDate>
            <guid>2026-01-08_evil</guid>
            <link>https://pnppl.cc/2026-01-08_evil</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2026-01-01_possessor</title>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-possessor--as-trans-horror&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Possessor&lt;/em&gt; as Trans Horror &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;-possessor--as-trans-horror&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#-possessor--as-trans-horror&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/essay&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;essay&#34; name=&#34;essay&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#essay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/horror&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;horror&#34; name=&#34;horror&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#horror&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/film&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;film&#34; name=&#34;film&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#film&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/trans-reading&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;trans-reading&#34; name=&#34;trans-reading&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#trans-reading&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;body-horror-and-gender-dysphoria&#34;&gt;Body horror and gender dysphoria &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;body-horror-and-gender-dysphoria&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#body-horror-and-gender-dysphoria&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Films in the body horror genre are replete with images and themes that resonate with trans viewers.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; name=&#34;fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Gender dysphoria is a very common aspect of trans subjectivity, and perhaps the most salient type is body dysphoria. &amp;quot;Body dysphoria&amp;quot; is, of course, nearly a synonym of &amp;quot;body horror&amp;quot;. Not all gender dysphoria rises to the intensity of &lt;em&gt;horror&lt;/em&gt;, and not all body horror trades on horror at one&#39;s own body, but it is unsurprising that there is a high degree of thematic overlap.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trans readings are most obvious in narratives of gradual degeneration that mirror the experience of unwanted puberty. In &lt;em&gt;The Fly&lt;/em&gt; (1986), Jeff Goldblum spends a great deal of time staring in a literal mirror, watching as he is slowly transformed into a monster with each passing day. Early in the process, he tries to shave insectile growths from his face; trans women often compare testosterone-induced body and facial hair to the legs of insects. While there are many possible readings, the puberty reading is an obvious one, even for cis viewers; puberty is a difficult experience for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another recurring trope in body horror is dissociation/derealization/depersonalization. Characters often observe their own mutilation with an eerie detachment, powerless or unwilling to stop it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderanalysis.net/depersonalization/&#34;&gt;This phenomenon is a common aspect of gender dysphoria&lt;/a&gt; that is powerfully depicted by Jane Schoenbrun and others working in the overlapping sister genre of psychological horror. Schoenbrun&#39;s masterpiece &lt;em&gt;I Saw The TV Glow&lt;/em&gt; (as well as their lesser work &lt;em&gt;We&#39;re All Going to the World&#39;s Fair&lt;/em&gt;) foregrounds a frequently co-occurring theme: technology as a force that drives and mediates personal alienation, and that also promises the possibility of transcending the limits of the flesh. &lt;em&gt;Videodrome&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;eXistenZ&lt;/em&gt; are other exemplars here. Neither techno-dissociation or -transcendance is uniquely trans, but again, the resonance is undeniable, particularly in the internet age.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More broadly, body horror highlights difficulties and discomfort with personal identity. It asks what (if anything) makes you you and whether it can be changed or taken away. While the popular transphobic notion of &amp;quot;gender confusion&amp;quot; is of little value — trans people are often less confused about their gender than cis people, who might not have ever thought about it — this is still a very trans theme: Is medical transition right for me? If I&#39;m forced to detransition, will I still be myself? Is my difference something I can celebrate? Does my sexed embodiment matter? What even is gender?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many works also lend themselves to a trans-hostile reading. They gawk at atypically sexed bodies and use transness as a visual shorthand for degeneration, emphasizing not the horror experienced by the tormented subject, but horror at the Other. Excessive, harmful, &amp;quot;unnatural&amp;quot; surgery is also a common trope. Films like &lt;em&gt;Tetsuo: The Iron Man&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Substance&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Crimes of the Future&lt;/em&gt; (2022) feature a protagonist addicted to harming their own body through surgical means. Sometimes the connection to trans identity is made explicit, such as with forced sex change narratives like &lt;em&gt;The Skin I Live In&lt;/em&gt; or gender variant characters like &lt;em&gt;Titane&lt;/em&gt;. And of course, horror as a whole has a long history of transphobic, sensationalized portrayals of transness, like &lt;em&gt;Psycho&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Silence of the Lambs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One final thing to note is the prevalence of graphic sex, especially &amp;quot;deviant&amp;quot; sex.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; name=&#34;fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This is often the hardest aspect to interpret because it can serve so many different ends. It can even serve opposing ones simultaneously. Is it intended to shock, titillate? Both? Is it incidental and only &amp;quot;deviant&amp;quot; insofar as the world of the story is unlike our own? Is the film providing a venue for sexual practices that are otherwise suppressed, or contributing to their suppression? Is this really sex, or is it actually rape? The one constant is that body horror can be relied on to showcase sexuality that is rarely depicted elsewhere. This is often relevant to trans people, who are disproportionately queer and probably disproportionately kinky, on top of frequently having a more complex relationship with their sexuality than the cishet average due to dysphoria, trauma, and cissexist expectations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-possessor--2020&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Possessor&lt;/em&gt; (2020) &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;-possessor--2020&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#-possessor--2020&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;!! This section contains spoilers. You should watch the film before reading it. Also, nudity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brandon Cronenberg&#39;s films are brilliant, yet they do not receive anywhere near the level of acclaim they deserve. His work is perhaps overshadowed by that of his father, to which it owes an obvious debt. It feels as though he spent his whole life marinating in Cronenberg the elder&#39;s work, letting it suffuse every pore, then burst onto the film scene in a blaze of originality. So far, his films are consistently excellent, where his father&#39;s are of more mixed quality, hitting both incredible highs and forgettable lows. Brandon takes David&#39;s skin-crawling surrealism and shapes it into razor-sharp, absolutely unsparing hard science fiction. You could say I&#39;m a fan. If you are unfamiliar with his work and have ten minutes to spare, check out his short film &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/please-speak-continuously-and-describe-your-experiences-as-they-come-to-you-2019_202403&#34;&gt;Please Speak Continuously and Describe Your Experiences as They Come to You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my money, &lt;em&gt;Possessor&lt;/em&gt; is the most criminally underrated of his films. His debut feature &lt;em&gt;Antiviral&lt;/em&gt; had some success among arthouse horror fans for its bizarre premise, and &lt;em&gt;Infinity Pool&lt;/em&gt; drew more mainstream attention. But &lt;em&gt;Possessor&lt;/em&gt;, which sits between the two chronologically, seems to have had a muted reception, despite being his best film. Set in the near future, it depicts a professional assassin who possesses her victims using high technology then causes them to commit murder-suicide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Going back to the common elements of body horror that I identified above as lending themselves to trans readings, it ticks off each box. The assassin, Tasya Vos, has lost herself in her job. Her mental state is degrading. When we first meet her, she chooses to stab her victim to death instead of using the gun she was provided. When it comes time to shoot herself, she is unable to do it. For a normal person, shooting yourself is a sign of poor mental health; for her, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; shooting herself means something has gone wrong. Physically and psychologically, she resembles a ghost. The technology that pays her bills has exacted a terrible toll. She is estranged from her husband and child and approaches meeting with them the same way she prepares for a job, practicing her lines to herself. Her &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; life is just another role she plays. After each job she undergoes psychological evaluation to verify that she is still, technically, herself. So we have degeneration, depersonalization, techno-alienation and -transcendance, and yes, a heaping scoop of uncensored sex.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, hecklers, you must forgive me for applying a trans lens to this film, because body horror&#39;s trans vibes are just the start. While Brandon Cronenberg is not, to my knowledge, transgender, and while the trans themes I identify are not exactly explicit, there&#39;s a lot more to this than &amp;quot;trans woman watches film, decides it&#39;s about gender&amp;quot;. There are somehow still people who deny that the magnificent &lt;em&gt;Being John Malkovich&lt;/em&gt; is the transest movie ever made by an ostensible cis man, and it has an explicitly trans character. Cis critics even denied that &lt;em&gt;I Saw The TV Glow&lt;/em&gt;, a movie about gender dysphoria made by a trans person, had anything to do with gender. So, if you find my analysis utterly ridiculous, may I gently suggest you adjust your worldview to one where cisness is not the default.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, here&#39;s what I think: gender dysphoria is central to &lt;em&gt;Possessor&lt;/em&gt; and you can&#39;t make any sense of it otherwise. I honestly don&#39;t think that can be reasonably contested.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More open to debate is my further reading: that Tasya Vos is a genderqueer or transmasculine person who has been corrupted by the patriarchy and by an unhealthy coping strategy. At the least, Vos is a figure tormented by gender dysphoria into becoming a monster. Whether you take this as hostile or sympathetic to trans people is not very important to me, but I would lean sympathetic. That might seem strange given the monstrosity Vos becomes, but the film encourages us to see things from Vos&#39;s perspective; and it&#39;s in keeping with horror&#39;s tendency to exploit our fear not of monsters, but of becoming a monster.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: I will from here on refer to Vos with neutral pronouns, not as a judgment call about the character&#39;s identity, but to encourage awareness of the ineherent ambiguity and discourage firm conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-calibrator&#34;&gt;The calibrator &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;the-calibrator&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#the-calibrator&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first shot of the film is of Vos inserting a needle-tipped probe into the skull of the first victim, ie, Vos&#39;s own skull. We later learn that this is a device for calibrating the connection between the host body and the assassin possessing it. Vos looks into the mirror while slowly turning up the dial on the device. The victim&#39;s face moves through a variety of emotions, ultimately sobbing in despair, then moves back to a forced calm. (This performance by Gabrielle Graham is fantastic, by the way. It&#39;s unsettling to see such realistic emotional lability with no apparent external source.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/calibrator.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think this device is one of the most intriguing things about the movie&#39;s universe, despite the fact that it undercuts the &amp;quot;perfect crime&amp;quot; nature of Vos&#39;s job — a minor plot hole we can easily overlook. The calibrator seemingly must be used in front of a mirror. It appears to stimulate a range of strong emotions in order to anchor the possessor in the host body, but the fact that it requires a mirror indicates that this anchoring process is about self-identification. Mirrors encourage us to consider the connection between the mind and body, the internal and external selves. By experiencing these emotions while watching them play across the host&#39;s face, Vos mentally connects the host&#39;s body with their own: I feel this; they feel this; therefore they = me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The device itself, though: it&#39;s a needle you insert that makes you feel more connected to your body. Sound familiar? Needles are a common delivery method for hormones, and strong emotions are often triggered immediately after an injection. It&#39;s tempting to read this as the sci-fi equivalent of HRT, but of course, it&#39;s being used to help Vos steal someone else&#39;s body, not feel more comfortable in their own. Instead of altering the body, it alters the mind. Thus, it might be closer to the &lt;em&gt;opposite&lt;/em&gt; of HRT: conversion therapy in a box.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;compatibility&#34;&gt;Compatibility &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;compatibility&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#compatibility&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Later, when Vos is assigned to possess Colin Tate, we&#39;re told (foreshadowing!) that his body is not very compatible with Vos, and so the mission will only last three to five days and the calibrator must be used at least daily. (Vos seems reticent to do this, probably because it&#39;s an unpleasant experience.) How we interpret this supposed incompatibility has significant implications for our understanding of Vos&#39;s gender identity. At first blush, one might assume that they are incompatible due to the fact that Colin is a man. And that might be true, but I increasingly suspect it&#39;s a red herring. There are all sorts of neurological reasons they might be incompatible, and as we saw in the beginning, the calibrator is still necessary when possessing a body with the same sex characteristics. We just don&#39;t have enough context to judge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I say &amp;quot;supposed incompatibility&amp;quot; because the film gives us reason to suspect the &amp;quot;incompatibility&amp;quot; is actually an &lt;em&gt;excess&lt;/em&gt; of compatibility. Vos&#39;s employers do not want them to become too attached to their life in the host. As things spiral out of control in the denouement, it&#39;s unclear where Vos ends and Colin begins. Vos even tells him, or themselves, that the murders were acts of his own agency: &lt;em&gt;You&#39;re the one in control.&lt;/em&gt; Maybe the whole thing is just a power struggle, and Vos said this to try to manipulate him into killing himself, but we are shown tons of visuals of the two of them blurring together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/mask.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Colin and Vos have a lot in common. They are both abused and exploited by incredibly invasive employers. They both work soul-killing jobs: Colin spies on &lt;del&gt;Amazon&lt;/del&gt; Zoothroo users and harvests data about the most boring things in the scene; Vos gives up their identity and murders people, regularly experiencing suffering that includes committing suicide. They are both directly overseen for the entirety of their time on the clock. Colin&#39;s job even incorporates VR for no apparent reason, meaning his consciousness is transferred to a new perspective, akin to her possessions. (Hilariously, he even has a virtual desk and monitor inside the VR environment.) Colin&#39;s job is voyeuristic, while Vos&#39;s takes voyeur to a whole new level. Both of them have an inappropriately close connection with their employer: Colin&#39;s is his horrible father-in-law, Vos&#39;s plays therapist and demands to know Vos&#39;s thoughts in addition to ordering and overseeing contract kills. When Vos is told to start a fight with Colin&#39;s father-in-law, the rage on display could have come from either one of them: &lt;em&gt;You think you can step on me? I&#39;m a giant!&lt;/em&gt; The cover story that Colin had a breakdown under all the stress might not have been far off the mark.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps militating against this reading is the fact that Vos has a breakdown at Colin&#39;s job when assigned to spy on a couple having sex. A naked woman lies spread eagle on the bed, then a naked man walks into frame and starts eating her out. Why is this the trigger? Is it because Vos doesn&#39;t feel at home in a man&#39;s body? Because it reminds them of the body they will return to? Because Colin is turned on by it and reasserts control? Is it an incompatibility in sexual orientation? I&#39;m not sure what to make of it, and it runs counter to some other observations, but it&#39;s clearly significant and tells us that sex/gender is central to the story.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;depersonalization-sex-and-masculinity&#34;&gt;Depersonalization, sex, and masculinity &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;depersonalization-sex-and-masculinity&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#depersonalization-sex-and-masculinity&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The couple being spied on by &lt;del&gt;Amazon&lt;/del&gt; Zoothroo is not the first significant sex scene. After Vos&#39;s first assignment is complete, they request time off to try to reconnect with their family. (Vos&#39;s boss is not happy about this, reminding Vos that they separated and that Vos decided it was better that way.) Vos approaches this like another assignment: they practice greeting their family with no apparent emotion, then seem to fake the emotions when the time comes. Their real life is just another role to play, motions to go through. Very pre-transition trans. Later, they initiate sex with their husband by laying their head on his arm like a puppy. Cut to fucking: Vos is just lying there in the missionary position, clearly feeling nothing, absolutely dead inside. It&#39;s only when they remember plunging a knife into their victim&#39;s body that they feel anything. At first, it seems like Vos is haunted by it... but then, they get aroused and bite their husband.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dead-inside.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What to make of this? Clearly Vos is no longer turned on by PIV with this man; what they really crave is violence. And notably, the form that violence takes is stabbing, the type most heavily freighted with psychosexual baggage: sticking something into the victim. This is a frequent trope in horror: women who are dispatched by repeated stabbing with a knife, echoing the violent insertion of a phallus. Recall too that Vos went out of their way to select a knife as the murder weapon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vos isn&#39;t forced to do this job. They could quit at any time, but they don&#39;t want to. It provides an outlet for something very dark that lurks inside them, an attraction to violence that is typically masculine. Vos&#39;s job is alienating them from their own humanity, but I think it&#39;s awakening something in them besides a love of violence. The simplest explanation is that they are sublimating their desire to sexually penetrate into a desire to violently penetrate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We get further evidence of this when Vos possesses Colin. One of the first things they do is examine themself in the mirror. They look at their penis, then pick up their fiancee&#39;s panties and look at the vaginal discharge. There&#39;s no evidence of arousal at this point; they act as detached as ever. But why examine the panties? Maybe they were just contemplating their new sex. They didn&#39;t smell them. Still, Vos seems to be attracted to Colin&#39;s fiancee immediately. They stare at her while she&#39;s getting dressed; they walk up behind her, put their arms around her, tell her she smells good, and kiss her. The fiancee, Ava, immediately notices something is off, but first identifies it as Colin being in a good mood. Maybe the staring was part of Vos&#39;s voyeuristic tendency to study people, and maybe the kissing — which mimics what Vos observed while prepping for the job  — was just a ploy to win Ava&#39;s trust. Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s really interesting is what happens when Vos and Ava fuck. Ava is on top in a distinctly dominant role: she puts her fingers in Vos/Colin&#39;s mouth, then wraps one hand around their neck and puts the other over their mouth. Vos grabs her hands and forces them behind her back, then sits up and flips them around so Ava is on her back. It&#39;s only at this point that Vos/Colin really seems to get into it. This is also when some &amp;quot;synchronization&amp;quot; issues begin to crop up: we see flickers of Vos&#39;s actual face; Vos/Colin looks uncomfortable; we see Colin screaming internally; Colin/Vos sits up. Then, Colin&#39;s body changes into Vos&#39;s, slim and breasted, except with a large penis. They continue thrusting it a little. With some reticence, they continue fucking. Closeups of an open eye are overlaid. Cut to Vos/Colin sitting alone with their head down in a pose suggestion exhaustion or dejection; they check in with their boss and say they are in perfect sync with the host.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dickgirl.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the closest we get to an explicit trans moment in the film, but it is very explicit. Vos is embodied in their mind&#39;s eye as a woman with a large penis, rather like a fetishistic depiction of a trans woman. I imagine this is a polarizing scene for transfem viewers. It seems to use our bodies as a symbol of confusion or ambiguity. However, that symbol literalizes what Vos/Colin is experiencing; I suspect whether it&#39;s offensive comes down to whether you feel it was done for shock value or not, which I don&#39;t really think it was.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just like the voyeuristic VR scene, sex has clearly triggered some sort of disconnect. And like the VR scene, it&#39;s not entirely clear why. One obvious explanation is that Vos is experiencing severe gender dysphoria leading to dissociation, but I don&#39;t think that quite fits. Vos seems numb and disconnected, yes, but that&#39;s how they always are; they literally &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; diconnected; it isn&#39;t their body. It&#39;s Colin whose face we see screaming in horror, presumably because he&#39;s powerless to stop this intruder from fucking his fiancee. Vos continues thrusting their cock, slightly, while they look down at themselves in detached wonder. And most significantly, the scene mirrors the earlier &amp;quot;dead inside&amp;quot; scene between Vos and their husband. Vos/Colin firmly rejects the submissive position that they occupied in the earlier sex scene and reverses it. This does not read as method acting to me: if they liked that role, they could have just kept it going; how they had sex had no relevance to the mission. Presumably Ava and Colin have had sex before and she knows what he likes; it&#39;s Vos who wants to be dominant.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; name=&#34;fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dom.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sex in &lt;em&gt;Possessor&lt;/em&gt; seems to function like the opposite of the calibrator. The powerful emotions and bodily sensations it generates provide an opportunity for the host&#39;s identity to break through and assert itself. Whether this is because it creates gender dysphoria in the possessor or because it connects strongly to the host&#39;s psyche, it&#39;s clear that &lt;em&gt;Possessor&lt;/em&gt; sees sexuality as fundamental to self-conception, even moreso than strong emotion alone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;suicide&#34;&gt;Suicide &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;suicide&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#suicide&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This may seem crass, but it feels significant to me that Vos&#39;s job centrally involves suicide. This is a topic that trans people are unfortunately quite familiar with. Our high suicide rates are now sufficiently well known that they are used to harass us and encourage us to inflict death on ourselves. As self-harm goes, the ability to kill yourself over and over again has got to take the cake.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why have they begun having trouble going through with it? The job is clearly fucking them up, alienating them from their own humanity, causing them to experience mental lapses that interfere with their performance, but we never learn exactly why it&#39;s started to be a problem now. Is it just how long they&#39;ve been doing the job? Never in the film do we see them successfully complete suicide. I think it fits with my point about &lt;a href=&#34;#compatibility&#34;&gt;compatibility&lt;/a&gt;: Vos is increasingly unable or unwilling to separate from the host body. Their ghostly, detached existence means there is less and less of them. They crave the taste of real existence that they get from their hosts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This entire approach to life makes sense as a maladaptive coping mechanism for untreated gender dysphoria. As miserable as Vos&#39;s job is, it&#39;s an escape from real life. They get to spend time in a body that is not their own, living a life that is not their own. It&#39;s the grisly equivalent of spending your life in a drunken stupor watching television. Metaphorically, Vos has already committed suicide. The violence that they inflict on others is nothing compared to what they inflict on themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;family-gender-roles-and-stereotypes&#34;&gt;Family, gender roles, and stereotypes &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;family-gender-roles-and-stereotypes&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#family-gender-roles-and-stereotypes&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some other, shallower reasons to read Vos as masculine. First of all, they&#39;re a professional murderer. That&#39;s statistically very unlikely for a woman. The personal items used to test their reintegration are stereotypically masculine: a butterfly they murdered, their grandfather&#39;s pipe. They also do not wear any makeup or other femme accoutrements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then there&#39;s their relationship with their family. Leaving your spouse to take care of your child alone while you go away to work is a common pattern for men, but much less common for women. Women typically fill the caring role at home while men fuck off. Not to mention that Vos seemingly only popped in to get their rocks off, then ditched, and the sex being bad seems like it sealed the deal on giving up on the family.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vos&#39;s boss is the voice of the patriarchy. She encourages Vos to sever ties with their family: they&#39;re holding Vos back; interfering with their work; they&#39;re a danger to their family anyway. They&#39;re Vos&#39;s last thread of connection to humanity, and that&#39;s inconvenient. The company needs a killing machine, not a loving parent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And of course, there&#39;s the finale. We learn that Vos&#39;s boss has possessed their child to ensure the mission is finished, and likely to ensure that Vos no longer has a family to steal their attention. In the end, it&#39;s Vos who annihilates their own child, screaming with the same hatred displayed during the earlier fight at the party. I speculated that that rage might have been genuinely Colin&#39;s; in this case, it is unambiguous that it genuinely belongs to Vos. This type of rage is about as male as it gets. It&#39;s unstable men who are prone to annihilate their family and themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/annihilation.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the final analysis, Vos&#39;s boss was right. She may have maneuvered them into the revelation, but the revelation was sincere. Vos&#39;s true feelings are that they despise their family and everything it represents. Empathy, domesticity, womanhood: Tasya Vos is not meant for these things. Their truth is unrestrained power and pounding blood. Their toxic masculinity is in service of a power structure that doesn&#39;t actually care about them — but since when is that new? Masculinity exists to turn men into weapons that protect male power.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Testosterone could have saved him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/tragic.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;Footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;Footnotes&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#Footnotes&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this, and all my writing, I don&#39;t intend to speak for others or imply what I say is true of all trans people. Far from it; we are as diverse as any people group. I&#39;m speaking from my own perspective, and generalize only because I think there are a non-negligible number of other trans people who have a similar perspective. Without the ability to assume some degree of shared experience, we wouldn&#39;t have the term &amp;quot;transgender&amp;quot; in the first place.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; name=&#34;fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would consider erotic horror another sister genre to body horror. Besides heavy overlap in both Cronenbergs&#39; films, see Julia Ducournau (&lt;em&gt;Raw&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Titane&lt;/em&gt;), Clive Barker&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Hellraiser&lt;/em&gt; series, &lt;em&gt;Possession&lt;/em&gt; (1981), &lt;em&gt;From Beyond&lt;/em&gt; (1986), &lt;em&gt;Under the Skin&lt;/em&gt; (2013), &lt;em&gt;The Substance&lt;/em&gt; (2024), and the entire &amp;quot;monsterfucker&amp;quot; genre. No really, see them, they&#39;re all good! Except for maybe the monsterfucker stuff. Do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; watch &lt;em&gt;La Bête&lt;/em&gt; (1975) unless you are really into simulated bigfoot rape and unsimulated horse sex. I should have turned it off when it opened with what felt like an hour of close-ups of horse cock. I watched it so you don&#39;t have to. It&#39;s amazing what you can find at your local library.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; name=&#34;fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I realize I&#39;m playing a little fast and loose with my sex terminology here. They&#39;re not exactly doing anything kinky. The change in position seems like a pretty vanilla exchange of power; normal give-and-take, not a clear dominant and submissive. But they shot the scene this way for a reason. They gave us close-ups of Ava&#39;s hand around Colin&#39;s throat and Colin&#39;s hands holding hers behind her back for a reason. I think that reason was to emphasize the shifting power in the scenario.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; name=&#34;fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-31T08:27:55-05:00</pubDate>
            <guid>2026-01-01_possessor</guid>
            <link>https://pnppl.cc/2026-01-01_possessor</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>index</title>
            <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;under-construction&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/index&#34;&gt;Under Construction&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;under-construction&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#under-construction&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please pardon our dust.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You might like to read &lt;a href=&#34;/about&#34;&gt;the about page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29T12:45:49-05:00</pubDate>
            <guid>index</guid>
            <link>https://pnppl.cc/index</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2025-12-12_trans-genocide</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-12_trans-genocide&#34;&gt;Trans Genocide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/essay&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;essay&#34; name=&#34;essay&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#essay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/politics&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;politics&#34; name=&#34;politics&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are trans people experiencing a genocide? Well, I hope we&#39;ve learned from Gaza that when people start splitting hairs about whether events &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; constitute genocide, something has gone terribly wrong. It does not at all reassure me that when I share my perfectly rational concerns,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; name=&#34;fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; what seemingly bothers people most is my choice of words.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Still, skepticism is an understandable response to an accusation of genocide.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; name=&#34;fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; After all, one motivation for using strong language like &amp;quot;genocide&amp;quot; is to draw attention to the severity of the issue, and that capacity might be compromised if the word is overused. As reasonable as it seems on its face, this line of criticism is ultimately tendentious. What is really at stake is not the capacity for words to stir emotion, but our capacity to speak meaningfully and truthfully. This category error contributed to years of handwringing, scolding, and generally irritating bullshit from the Serious Person Squad over whether we were allowed to call Donald Trump a fascist. It is not particularly important whether calling someone a &amp;quot;Nazi&amp;quot; arouses your feelings, but it is important whether that someone actually is a Nazi. After all, nobody will be stirred into action against said Nazi if they can&#39;t even identify him as one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But that doesn&#39;t get us all the way to a G-card — the identification still needs to be correct, and Serious People contend it isn&#39;t. So, down to brass tacks: what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; genocide, anyway? At this point, we could invoke a formal definition. There&#39;s actually one inscribed in law at the UN.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; name=&#34;fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We could also run down a list of features of genocide as identified by experts and tick off the ones that apply.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; name=&#34;fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (We could even use a dictionary, that old bellwether of bad internet arguments.) And there&#39;s obviously a place in the world for this sort of legalistic approach, but I don&#39;t think we need any of that here. The meaning of a word and its definition are two different things. A definition attempts to capture meaning that&#39;s already there, and I think we know what genocide is: it&#39;s when someone tries to wipe out an entire group of people. We&#39;re watching one, on our phones. Genocide is when humans treat each other the same way they treat an infestation of cockroaches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, is that happening to trans people? After all, they aren&#39;t dropping bombs on us. There&#39;s no paramilitary systematically murdering every trans person they can find. (Yet.) But there are many methods to wipe out an infestation, and there&#39;s no sense wasting all that effort when you can just put out poisoned roach traps. Maybe a better question is this: &lt;strong&gt;how would a world where trans people were treated like an infestation &lt;em&gt;differ&lt;/em&gt; from our own?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t think of anything. Having the social status of a cockroach is just a straightforward description of life as a trans person. Accepting that status is the cost you know you have to pay to truly live.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; name=&#34;fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Many trans people live this way: hiding during the day, scurrying out at night, surviving on crumbs and human forbearance. Nobody&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; name=&#34;fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; denies that society treats trans people very badly, but we&#39;ve always &lt;em&gt;been&lt;/em&gt; cockroaches. Why are we getting so worked up about it &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;, when we&#39;ve been treated like dirt for ages?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My answer is this: &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-12_trans-genocide&#34;&gt;trans genocide&lt;/a&gt; is not a new phenomenon. Like Israel&#39;s recent slaughter of Palestinians and wholesale destruction of their country, we can clearly identify a sharp increase in the oppression, but it&#39;s part of a longer process. The Holocaust did not begin the moment the first gas chamber was turned on; the mass murder was preceeded by years of escalating oppression. Trans people have been surviving genocidal conditions for most of our history. When transphobia is swept aside as simple intolerance — an unavoidable social ill, not a calamity — it masks the physical realities of oppression: children abused and taught to hide and hate what they are; teenagers made homeless by their own parents; young women raped and disposed of in dumpsters; staggering numbers of people choosing death over this life.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; name=&#34;fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Violence and abuse against trans people are pervasive throughout our society to such an extent that our numbers were held firmly at ~0% of the population until the internet empowered us to organize without scurrying out and getting stomped on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, this genocidal social context has been so thoroughly normalized that it also affects how trans people think. We&#39;re fish in water. We have low expectations for how we&#39;ll be treated, and work around it as best we can, like anyone does with obstacles in their daily life. So when conditions have worsened to the point where we flee our homes en masse,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; name=&#34;fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; we can be confident the situation has become catastrophic, even if it gets us no closer to determining if a genocide has &amp;quot;officially&amp;quot; begun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason things have deteriorated so badly is not complicated: there are people who want to wipe us out, and they have a great deal of money and power. Like Hitler and Ben-Gvir, they do not take great pains to hide this fact. Perhaps the most famous example was when Michael Knowles took the stage at CPAC and announced that &amp;quot;transgenderism must be eradicated from public life entirely&amp;quot;,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; name=&#34;fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but the dedicated cockroach-stompers have always been clear about their intentions. Janice Raymond&#39;s landmark 1979 book The Transsexual Empire — basically, Mein Kampf for feminists who hate trans women — says that &amp;quot;the problem of transsexualism would best be served by morally mandating it out of existence&amp;quot;. Women&#39;s Declaration International (then WHRC), a major psuedofeminist hate outfit backed by all the prominent transphobes,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; name=&#34;fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; submitted a document to UK Parliament that calls for the &amp;quot;elimination of ... the practice of transgenderism&amp;quot;.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; name=&#34;fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Eliminating trans people is a clear priority for the Trump regime, though they prefer the euphemism &amp;quot;gender ideology&amp;quot;.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:12&#34; name=&#34;fnref:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Anyone who has ever lived among Republicans knows they generally feel the same way; random congressmen volunteer suggestions like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have to get them off the streets, and we have to get them off the internet, and we can’t let them communicate with each other. I’m all about free speech, but this is a virus, this is a cancer.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:13&#34; name=&#34;fnref:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But of course, we don&#39;t need any admission of motive. Their actions speak loudly enough. Why else would you ban medication that saves trans people&#39;s lives, if not to kill them? How much more obvious could their intentions possibly be? It&#39;s cold-blooded murder. It&#39;s no different than if they were to ban insulin: not &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the diabetics would die, but it is not exactly hard to connect the causal dots. And that&#39;s only the tip of the iceberg when it comes to cruel, illegal, and exterminationist policy. They have two apparent policy priorities: 1) to make the world as hostile as possible to trans people, with an emphasis on children who can&#39;t fight back and on causing psychological devastation; 2) to erase trans people from society by banning and covering up our identities, language, and history. These two prongs meet to create what I think of as their worst crime: they aren&#39;t just erasing history and killing our loved ones, they&#39;re banning the future. They want to rob us of hope for a better tomorrow and ensure that the next generation of trans people has to start over from scratch.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:14&#34; name=&#34;fnref:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, trans people will always exist. But how many of them? What will their lives be like, and how long will they be? Will they even have the language to describe themselves?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t have to call it a genocide. It&#39;s just a word. You can call it pre-genocide, incitement, red flags, or whatever you want. But you cannot deny that our society has been swept by a powerful campaign to crush trans people like bugs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;Footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;Footnotes&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#Footnotes&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve been told time and again that transmisogynist bigots&#39; completely baseless fears must be pandered to, because they have &amp;quot;reasonable concerns&amp;quot;. Reasonableness apparently requires no evidence, just technical plausibility. Trans people&#39;s fear of persecution is not only reasonable, it&#39;s backed with mountains of actual evidence, so we ought to be in solid epistemic territory. But who gets accused of overreacting?&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; name=&#34;fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Skepticism is the correct default posture to &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; claims, as long as you don&#39;t mistake willful ignorance for it.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; name=&#34;fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This definition was arguably compromised by the same eliminationist bigotry toward trans and queer people which it fails to identify. After WWII, the Allies did not free the gay people imprisoned by the Nazis, continued arresting them, and reflexively erased them from Holocaust memory.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; name=&#34;fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have taken this approach before, and it doesn&#39;t seem to have any effect. People just treat you like a lawyer arguing a technicality. Instead of elevating the affect of a word over its meaning, they conflate the two. You&#39;re giving them a definition, but they know the meaning is what really matters, and they judge whether that meaning applies based on whether they feel sufficiently outraged.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; name=&#34;fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s an absolute bargain, but it&#39;s still not one anyone should have to make.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; name=&#34;fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;...who matters&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; name=&#34;fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not consider this suicide; it is better understood as social murder.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; name=&#34;fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/us-internal-refugee-crisis-130-260k&#34;&gt;https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/us-internal-refugee-crisis-130-260k&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; name=&#34;fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve followed my cockroach analogy, you&#39;ll understand that the fig leaf of specifically &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; life is utterly without meaning. The ability to live in public, and the ability to live, full stop, are functionally identical. Knowles wants the cockroaches to run back into the walls.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; name=&#34;fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Except, curiously, JK Rowling, as far as I can tell. At least, she didn&#39;t sign their &amp;quot;Declaration on Women&#39;s Sex-Based Rights&amp;quot; (&lt;em&gt;eyeroll&lt;/em&gt;). At the time she was a little more circumspect about her trans hatred and just did stuff like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thepinknews.com/2022/04/11/jk-rowling-lunch-get-the-l-out-anti-trans-rosie-duffield/&#34;&gt;post photos sipping mimosas&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20220412023808/https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-10707447/JK-Rowling-enjoys-meal-prominent-feminists-backing-Respect-Sex-campaign.html&#34;&gt;with the genocidaires&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; name=&#34;fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/17510/html/&#34;&gt;https://committees.parliament.uk/writtenevidence/17510/html/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; name=&#34;fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:12&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20250121015439/https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/defending-women-from-gender-ideology-extremism-and-restoring-biological-truth-to-the-federal-government/&#34;&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20250121015439/https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/defending-women-from-gender-ideology-extremism-and-restoring-biological-truth-to-the-federal-government/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:12&#34; name=&#34;fn:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lgbtqnation.com/2025/09/gop-rep-says-we-need-to-remove-all-trans-people-from-streets-the-internet/&#34;&gt;https://www.lgbtqnation.com/2025/09/gop-rep-says-we-need-to-remove-all-trans-people-from-streets-the-internet/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:13&#34; name=&#34;fn:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:14&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the spurious legalistic rejoinders to &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-12_trans-genocide&#34;&gt;trans genocide&lt;/a&gt; is that we don&#39;t qualify as &amp;quot;a people&amp;quot;; we are a naturally occurring variation of humans, so it is not possible to ever completely wipe us out. Setting aside that the feasibility of committing total genocide is not actually relevant, this analysis ignores the reality of our lives. We belong to trans communities; we have a shared culture, history, and political interests; we have built up the collective knowledge we need to flourish and the tenuous capacity to pass that knowledge on to the next generation, who we dearly hope will build on our progress and enjoy better lives. All of that capacity can be smashed to pieces, and in fact it already has been once recently, when the Nazis set us back 60 years.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:14&#34; name=&#34;fn:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29T12:26:42-05:00</pubDate>
            <guid>2025-12-12_trans-genocide</guid>
            <link>https://pnppl.cc/2025-12-12_trans-genocide</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2025-12-10_gender-ideology</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;Gender Ideology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/essay&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;essay&#34; name=&#34;essay&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#essay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/politics&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;politics&#34; name=&#34;politics&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#politics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Gender ideology&amp;quot; is how members of the anti-trans movement refer to social acceptance of trans people and to associated ideas and practices. Like all buzzwords bandied by fascists, it has no particular meaning: it can be expanded to encompass all the things they don&#39;t like. Hence, it is also a conspiracy theory: Bad Things are not just Bad, they are also components of a larger Big Bad Miasma, echoing Nazi rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But of course, they are right that there is an ideological current opposed to theirs. Normally people would refer to this as &amp;quot;gender politics&amp;quot;. Everyone has gender politics, but in the fevered imagination of trans exterminationists, only trans people and our allies have them; everyone else just has common sense (and is definitely NOT being swept along by the dangerous ideology of a hate movement!). Many have remarked on the obviously ideological nature of the anti-trans movement, which comes through clearest in their immunity to evidence. If anyone is operating on pure ideology, it&#39;s them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, let&#39;s take it as a given that there is such a thing as &amp;quot;gender ideology&amp;quot;, but remove its conspiracist trappings: the anti-trans movement has a &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt;, and so do we, the people who oppose it. Let&#39;s call this opposing ideology &amp;quot;trans lib&amp;quot; for short. (I will refer to the anti-trans side as &amp;quot;fascist&amp;quot;.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; name=&#34;fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) What are the actual components of the trans lib &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt;, and how do we distinguish it from the &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt; of fascists?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think we can summarize it very simply: the &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt; of trans lib is &lt;em&gt;not enforceable by rape&lt;/em&gt;. Fascist &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt;, however, &lt;em&gt;can be&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; name=&#34;fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bold claim? I think not. Let&#39;s take an inventory of the beliefs one must hold to fall on the side of trans lib:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People are entitled to bodily autonomy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Further, people are entitled to basic dignity when they exercise their bodily autonomy in unpopular ways, eg by transitioning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How could you possibly enforce bodily autonomy and basic dignity with sexual violence? Sure, we can imagine some lurid horrors lurking in the imaginations of people like JK Rowling, wherein hulking trans women rape cis women until they accept their identity; and we have their oft-repeated smears that basic social acceptance is somehow tantamount to rape, in a mysterious metaphysical way. But it just wouldn&#39;t be coherent. Anyone who actually attempted it would be fundamentally in violation of trans lib &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt;. You can&#39;t spread bodily autonomy and dignity with rape! You just can&#39;t, no matter what that girl and her dragon tattoo say. Trans lib &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt; is fundamentally an anti-rape belief system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now let&#39;s turn to the opposing side. What do they believe?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People are not entitled to bodily autonomy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Further, people should be subjected to harm when they exercise their bodily autonomy in unpopular ways, eg by transitioning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s plenty of window dressing on it,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; name=&#34;fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but it boils down to an inversion of trans lib. Fascist &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt; might not &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; sexual violence, but it is &lt;em&gt;entirely consistent with it&lt;/em&gt;. There is no contradiction in using rape to harm people and take away their bodily autonomy. That&#39;s its whole purpose!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I&#39;m not speaking hypothetically. Even more unfortunately, I&#39;m not speaking hyperbolically. This essay was prompted by the announcement that the Trump regime has canceled the already paltry protections against sexual violence for imprisoned trans, intersex, and queer people afforded by the Prison Rape Elimination Act.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; name=&#34;fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In other words, the fascist regime is using state-sanctioned rape as a tool to enforce their &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt;. As horrifying as this is, it is not a new ideological development; it&#39;s baked in. The anti-trans movement has fought for years to ensure trans women are placed in men&#39;s prisons, where it is known the majority of them will be repeatedly raped — at rates far exceeding those of the rest of the population.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; name=&#34;fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even if we skip over these visceral horrors, the anti-trans movement still thrives on sexual violence and conceptually related harms. They have fought for the right to sexually harass trans children in schools by repeatedly misgendering and misnaming them,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; name=&#34;fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for institutions to out students to their parents for abuse,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; name=&#34;fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; title=&#34;[see footnote]&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for institutions to expose students to ostracism and ridicule with discriminatory bathroom rules, and on and on. This a movement that considers it laudable to confront someone in an intimate setting like a changing room or bathroom, harass them, demand they prove their sex, and even physically attack them — all based on their perception of the victim&#39;s gender. If my analysis is wrong, they aren&#39;t trying very hard to disprove it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More fundamentally, what could possibly be more invasive than forcing someone to go through an unwanted puberty? Few things are more harmful, more detrimental to dignity, than turning someone&#39;s own body against them. For all their protestations of metaphysical rape-by-proximity-to-trans-women, their designs are far darker: to control the basic sexual characteristics of their victims. They have another slur that is appropriate here: grooming. This is the core of the anti-trans movement&#39;s fascist &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt;: coercing children to sexually develop the way they prefer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;Footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes &lt;a class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#TOC&#34;&gt;&amp;not;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a name=&#34;Footnotes&#34; class=&#34;show-on-parent-hover is-hidden has-text-grey&#34; href=&#34;#Footnotes&#34;&gt;&amp;sect;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not give a shit whether you agree with my word choice. Take it as a given, like my use of &amp;quot;gender ideology&amp;quot;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; name=&#34;fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In practice, fascists &lt;em&gt;frequently&lt;/em&gt; enforce their &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt; via rape. Arguably, sexual violence is their &lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_gender-ideology&#34;&gt;gender ideology&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s defining feature.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; name=&#34;fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, they justify harming trans people on the basis that allowing bodily autonomy would constitute a greater, more grievous harm: the end of the family unit, loss of white reproductive capacity, conjectured future regret, blasphemy against god...&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; name=&#34;fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/2025/12/04/nx-s1-5630490/prison-doj-safety-memo-changes-trans-lgbtq-inmates&#34;&gt;https://www.npr.org/2025/12/04/nx-s1-5630490/prison-doj-safety-memo-changes-trans-lgbtq-inmates&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; name=&#34;fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V-coding&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V-coding&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; name=&#34;fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely a form of sexual harassment and I wish more people would identify it as such. Just imagine a cisgender boy being repeatedly called &amp;quot;she&amp;quot; because people think he&#39;s too swishy, or a cisgender girl who&#39;s always referred to as &amp;quot;Mike&amp;quot; because they think she&#39;s too butch. Most people would recognize this as obvious sexual harassment: singling someone out due to perceptions of their sex characteristics and making their life miserable. But when the victim is transgender, basic moral intuition goes out the window. Even nonhumans who are &amp;quot;misgendered&amp;quot; receive more dignity than this, and they don&#39;t even know what a pronoun is.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; name=&#34;fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most sexual abuse is committed by people close to the victim. &amp;quot;Corrective rape&amp;quot; is a real phenomenon. These things are connected.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; name=&#34;fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; title=&#34;[back to reference]&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&lt;-|&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29T03:58:20-05:00</pubDate>
            <guid>2025-12-10_gender-ideology</guid>
            <link>https://pnppl.cc/2025-12-10_gender-ideology</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2025-12-10_rosemary</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_rosemary&#34;&gt;Rosemary,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you always smell absolutely perfect.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you are an edible flower.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you draw me in through all my senses.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;i want to devour you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_rosemary&#34;&gt;Rosemary,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you make everything better.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;from the fanciest focaccia to the simplest stew,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;everything tastes better with you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_rosemary&#34;&gt;Rosemary,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you linger after you&#39;re gone.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;i smell you on my breath, my clothes.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;my kitchen has been claimed by you,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and my bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;autolink&#34; href=&#34;/2025-12-10_rosemary&#34;&gt;Rosemary,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;i&#39;m not much of a chef.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;i cannot do you justice.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;i&#39;m no gardener.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;your vivacity is as foreign to me as it is beautiful.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you made my life fragrant,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and i merely digested you.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;you deserve to be savored.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/+/tag/poem&#34; class=&#34;tag&#34; id=&#34;poem&#34; name=&#34;poem&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#poem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29T03:56:36-05:00</pubDate>
            <guid>2025-12-10_rosemary</guid>
            <link>https://pnppl.cc/2025-12-10_rosemary</link>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>